<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Denver Noell</title>
    <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Denver Noell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Scanned and Organized 10,000 Photos using VBA and Excel</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/jim-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/jim-martin/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think that many people would have guessed the amount of changes that would happen in 2020. There have been many hardships and unexpected difficulties such as job losses and businesses having to close. This has also been a time for reconnecting with loved ones and having extra time to work on projects and new interests. Personally, a positive impact was that this has given me more time to spend with my family that I wouldn’t have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VBA Made Easy</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/vba-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/vba-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>I started a new job in 2020. Little did I know that this would spend me spyrolling into learning many programming languages.
During the interview, questions about my experience with Excel came up. During my first week, one of my coworkers asked a question about a project that I had talked about in my interview. He proceeded to tell me that they sometimes used macros using VBA to do some of their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got started with Linux</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/linux/</guid>
      <description>When Covid hit my city pretty hard, my company descided to switch to remote work in order to mitigate risk. In our office, employees have dual-monitor set ups. To anyone who has never had a dual or tri-monitor set up, try it, you&amp;rsquo;ll like it. Because of this, our boss reccommended getting a second monitor if we did not already have one so that we could mimic our office set up as well as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created a website and so can you</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/web_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/web_start/</guid>
      <description>HTML I watched a video about how to host a website for free with Github Pages. They showed that html5up.net had many templates that could be used and edited for free that actually look really cool. Going to the site I downloaded a couple of the templates and started looking at the HTML. Fun fact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know HTML at the time. So I watched a crash course to teach me the basics of what different elements were used for and how they affected the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moment of Inertia Calculator</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/moment-of-inertia-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/moment-of-inertia-calculator/</guid>
      <description>In my Design of Steel Structures course, in order to calculate needed values for beams. The Moment of Inertia, Centroid, and related properties need to be calculated. Shapes included in the AISC Steel Manual have these values calculated but if there is a member not included in the manual or if it is a built up member, then it needs to be calculated by hand.
This led me to find a simple example on YouTube in order to break the problem down into variables that could make it work for any situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel Helper</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/steel-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/steel-helper/</guid>
      <description>Starting my Steel class, I could tell immediately that the problems in this class had lots of opportunity to be programmed due to the reliance on code. This means that any cutting back on referring to the code book can be very beneficial.
While solving problems I found that although there were many different starting conditions, most of the problems were to determine the same outputs. Because of this I created an ending function that took all of the outputs from previous functions to output the required strengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTex in Word</title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/latex_in_word/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/latex_in_word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic LaTeX equations to get started using LaTeX equation in Microsoft Word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/quarentine_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//denvernoell.netlify.app/blog/quarentine_experience/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think that many people would have guessed the amount of changes that would happen in 2020. There have been many hardships and unexpected difficulties such as job losses and businesses having to close. This has also been a time for reconnecting with loved ones and having extra time to work on projects and new interests. Personally, a positive impact was that this has given me more time to spend with my family that I wouldn’t have had.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>